

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>/</id>
  <title>Lahiru's dev journal</title>
  <subtitle>Hey, I'm Lahiru Pathirage. I've been professionally building software since 2016, working on everything from simple tools to complex enterprise systems. One thing that’s always held true for me is that good design leads to great software. I'm deeply focused on AI agents and serverless architecture; building systems that are intelligent, scalable, and require minimal human intervention. I'm a computer science graduate who feels at home in a terminal, loves Linux, and believes open source makes everything better.</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-07-13T00:07:23+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lahiru Sandaruwan Pathirage</name>
    <uri>/</uri>
  </author>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"
    href="/"/>
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <rights> © 2025 Lahiru Sandaruwan Pathirage </rights>
  <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo>


  
  <entry>
    <title>I've Noticed AI Tools Generate Terrible REST APIs - Here's How to Fix It</title>
    <link href="/posts/ive-noticed-ai-tools-generate-terrible-rest-apis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I've Noticed AI Tools Generate Terrible REST APIs - Here's How to Fix It" />
    <published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+05:30</published>
  
    <updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
  
    <id>/posts/ive-noticed-ai-tools-generate-terrible-rest-apis/</id>
    <content src="/posts/ive-noticed-ai-tools-generate-terrible-rest-apis/" />
    <author>
      <name>lpsandaruwan</name>
    </author>

  
    
    <category term="Posts" />
    
    <category term="REST" />
    
    <category term="API designing" />
    
    <category term="Software Engineering" />
    
    <category term="AI Assisted coding" />
    
  

  
    <summary>
      





      Here’s something that bugs me: AI tools like ChatGPT, Claude, Gemini, or whatever AI you’re using are great at cranking out code fast,
but they often generate REST APIs that look like they were designed by someone who never had to maintain them.

Over the past few years working with different teams, I’ve noticed that about most of AI-generated APIs have naming conventions that make me question ...
    </summary>
  

  </entry>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Arch Linux for Developers: A Step-by-Step Guide to Building Your Ultimate Dev Environment</title>
    <link href="/posts/archlinux-2024-guide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arch Linux for Developers: A Step-by-Step Guide to Building Your Ultimate Dev Environment" />
    <published>2024-10-27T00:00:00+05:30</published>
  
    <updated>2024-11-05T11:31:55+05:30</updated>
  
    <id>/posts/archlinux-2024-guide/</id>
    <content src="/posts/archlinux-2024-guide/" />
    <author>
      <name>lpsandaruwan</name>
    </author>

  
    
    <category term="Posts" />
    
    <category term="Linux" />
    
    <category term="OS" />
    
    <category term="Development" />
    
  

  
    <summary>
      





      

Why Arch Linux? Let’s Jump In!

Hey there, fellow developer community! If you’ve been browsing Linux distributions, you know there are tons of options out there. I’ve tested a few, gone on some Linux adventures, and finally landed on Arch Linux. And, wow, it’s been my go-to for over 11 years now. If you want a powerful development setup and want to learn Linux hands-on, Arch could be your gol...
    </summary>
  

  </entry>

  
  <entry>
    <title>GrooveCraft: Building Your Own Amplifier for Next-Level Music Vibes</title>
    <link href="/posts/crafting-audio-ecosystem/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GrooveCraft: Building Your Own Amplifier for Next-Level Music Vibes" />
    <published>2023-12-23T00:00:00+05:30</published>
  
    <updated>2023-12-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
  
    <id>/posts/crafting-audio-ecosystem/</id>
    <content src="/posts/crafting-audio-ecosystem/" />
    <author>
      <name>lpsandaruwan</name>
    </author>

  
    
    <category term="Posts" />
    
    <category term="Audio" />
    
    <category term="Hobby" />
    
    <category term="Music" />
    
  

  
    <summary>
      





      
  People have different preferences when it comes to how they like to listen to music, and the sound experience can be different for each person. Here, I’ve put together my findings on creating an affordable do-it-yourself sound system that suits my taste.




What Makes Sound Good?

Okay, so everyone’s got their own taste in sound. Some love the deep, thumping bass that makes your heart go bo...
    </summary>
  

  </entry>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Saga Pattern with serverless model on Google Cloud Platform - Part 1</title>
    <link href="/posts/saga-gcp-choreography/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Saga Pattern with serverless model on Google Cloud Platform - Part 1" />
    <published>2022-11-20T00:00:00+05:30</published>
  
    <updated>2023-11-03T21:56:02+05:30</updated>
  
    <id>/posts/saga-gcp-choreography/</id>
    <content src="/posts/saga-gcp-choreography/" />
    <author>
      <name>lpsandaruwan</name>
    </author>

  
    
    <category term="Posts" />
    
    <category term="Serverless" />
    
  

  
    <summary>
      





      
  Gostep: 👉 Guide
Materials: 👉 Complete source code


During the past few years, the microservices architecture(MSA) and serverless model have gained a lot of popularity in the industry. However, these technologies come with their own set of challenges. One substantial challenge is managing data in MSA due to its complexity. Considering common patterns for MSA data management we will be focusi...
    </summary>
  

  </entry>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Super charge a Google cloud functions project</title>
    <link href="/posts/gostep-intro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Super charge a Google cloud functions project" />
    <published>2020-06-19T00:00:00+05:30</published>
  
    <updated>2023-11-03T21:56:02+05:30</updated>
  
    <id>/posts/gostep-intro/</id>
    <content src="/posts/gostep-intro/" />
    <author>
      <name>lpsandaruwan</name>
    </author>

  
    
    <category term="Projects" />
    
    <category term="DevOps" />
    
  

  
    <summary>Bootstrap a micro services project with Google cloud functions quickly.</summary>
  

  </entry>

</feed>


